Kin Lon Choi

Address: 62 Cedar Avenue, Wickford, Essex, SS129DX Email: kinlonchoi@gmail.com Mobile number: 07712636191 GitHub: https://github.com/KinLonChoi

I am a highly motivated individual with six years of experience in the science industry looking for a career change to pursue my interest in programming. I have self-taught knowledge of coding in both front and backend languages. I am keen to develop new skills required to become an integral part of a software team.

Skills

- Well-versed in web technologies HTML and CSS with responsive designs using bootstrap framework.
- GitHub website: https://kinlonchoi.github.io/Portfolio/index.html
- Working knowledge of backend languages JavaScript and Python. Python projects: https://github.com/KinLonChoi/Python-Projects
- SQL knowledge using Database Management Software SQLite.
- Familiar with programming paradigms such as algorithms, data structures and software development lifecycles (SDLC).
- Accustom to working under time pressure to deliver the results necessary to achieve customer requirements in a timely fashion.
- Experience in data analytics, preparation, and presentation of technical reports according to Good Manufacturing Practice (GMP) auditing standards.
- Effective at working independently during product/method development and as a team to maintain high-quality standards throughout the quality department.

Employment

Sept 2016 - Sept 2021

Tate & Lyle PLC

Laboratory Analyst

- Specialised in ensuring products meet the required standards through meticulous testing throughout the production process.
- Designed and implemented appropriate analytic strategies for unique projects.
- Collaborated with other departments and developed continuous improvement strategies.
- Trained and certified in GMP auditing. I audited refinery areas and produced feedback reports on non-conformances.

Feb 2016 – Sept 2016

Tate & Lyle PLC

Research scientist

- Planned and conducted experiments for the innovation of new product development and continuous improvement projects.
- Exchanged information with colleagues in meetings to maintain steady progress on several projects.
- Prioritised and allocated time efficiently whilst working on several projects simultaneously.

Education/Certification

SQL For Data Science by University of California, Davis (Coursera)

Python for Everybody by University of Michigan (Coursera)

HTML, CSS, and JS for Web Developers by Johns Hopkins University (Coursera)

2011-2015 MChem (Hons) in Chemistry (2:1)

University of Leicester

2003-2011 The Bromfords School, Essex

A-Levels in Chemistry (B), Biology (B), and Physics (B)

10 GCSEs at A*-C including Chemistry, Maths, and English